Email: cs.bradbury@outlook.com Mobile: +44 7383514483

# **Calum Bradbury**

58 Priory Walk, Leicester, UK, LE3 3PP

### **Summary**

I am a driven and adaptable final year Masters of Electrical & Electronic Engineering (MEng) student with real-world work experience in a range of positions. Analytically minded and very enthusiastic about technology, I have experience in a wide assortment of software and programming languages. I thrive off positive results and have a great desire to learn new skills and improve existing ones further.

### Education

# MEng Electrical & Electronic Engineering (Hons), University of Nottingham, UK Sept 2016 – Present

- Achieved degree classification: First-Class Honours (1st).
- Thesis: An Artificial Neural Network for Microwave-Photonic Applications.
- Relevant modules include Advanced Computational Engineering (87%), Scalable Cross-Platform Software Design (72%), Computer Aided Engineering (71%) and Discrete Mathematics (Canadian grade A).

# Study year abroad Concordia University, QC, Canada Sept 2017–May 2018

- Demonstrated the commitment to personal improvement and the drive to take on new challenges through studying abroad.
- Showcased the ability to adapt to new situations and improved communication skills in another language through living in a province where French is the official language.

#### Professional Experience

### Student IT Support Tutor University of Nottingham Medical School, UK Sept 2019 – May 2020

• Developed customer service and technical skills through supporting medical school staff and students at the Queen's Medical Centre hospital with the university IT services, as well as any issues with personal and professional electronic devices.

# Software Developer Power Vigilance, Nottingham, UK 29<sup>th</sup> April 2019 – 10<sup>th</sup> May 2019

- Two week internship working on the development of a new online client portal for a small Nottingham based start-up Company.
- Successfully suggested and implemented multiple new features to the client portal including a freshly designed progress bar for the illustration of power usage in a client's building.

#### Advanced Manufacturing Labs intern University Of Nottingham, UK June 2018 – Sept 2018

- Summer internship in the University Of Nottingham Advanced Manufacturing Laboratory.
  Tasked with the design of a bespoke end-effector for a robot to process bio-materials with, in order to allow a local company to automate their current processes.
- Experience gained using Python, Robot Operating Software (ROS) and SOLIDWORKS.
- Successfully used 3D CAD software (SOLIDWORKS) to design the end-effector and programmed the robot to operate it in order to process bio-materials taken from a local hospital (Queens Medical Centre, Nottingham, UK).

**Operations Technician** 

Caterpillar Inc, Leicester, UK.

Sept 2014 - July 2016

- Employed full time within a team of colleagues manufacturing hydraulic values for backhoe loader diggers.
- Worked effectively and diligently in a high pressure and fast-paced environment.

#### Volunteer Experience

### Library Assistant Leicester Forest East Community Library, Leicester, UK June 2019 – Sept 2019

- Summer volunteer at local library assisting patrons with the online catalogue system.
- Utilized strong attention to detail to organize library shelves and restock returned books.
- Assisted patrons with any IT queries and issues.

# Course Representative University Of Nottingham, UK Sept 2016 – June 2017

- Course representative in first year of undergraduate degree tasked with reporting any issues with the course to the heads of the department.
- Responsibilities included being the first port of call for students if they had problems of any kind and gathering feedback to be communicated at monthly meetings with lecturers and heads of the department.

## Additional Skills & Qualifications:

- C/C++
- JavaScript
- HTML5 & CSS
- React.js
- Level 1 Health & Safety in the Workplace
- Lumerical Photonic Simulation Software
- Python
- MATLAB
- SOLIDWORKS
- Full Driving License

# **Additional Interests**

### Latin & Ballroom Dancing University of Nottingham DanceSport Team Sept 2019 – May 2020

- As a Member of the University of Nottingham DanceSport Team I competed in multiple national Ballroom & Latin dance competitions. Including the Inter Varsity Dance Championships (IVDC) at the Winter Gardens in Blackpool.
- Demonstrated discipline, dedication, and willingness to step out of my comfort zone when competing in front of hundreds or thousands of spectators.

#### **Studying French**

• I thoroughly enjoy studying the French language and have done so at night school whilst working full time and during my final year of University. Again, demonstrating my desire and drive to always learn and challenge myself.